اعوذ بالله من الشّيطن الرّجيم ۝بسم الله الرَحمن الرَحيم۝
الحمدلله و الصَلوة والسَلام على سيَدنا محمَدوعلى اله وصحبه وسلَم تسليماً كثيراً
To all my brothers and sisters who are listening this evening,
السلام عليكم ورحمة الله وبركاته
We ask Allahعزَوجلَ to make it easy for all of us, and to benefit us, and to provide us, with beneficial knowledge.
Allahعَزَّوجَل says;
وَقَالُوا لَوْلَاُ نُزِّلَ هَٰذَا الْقُرْآنُ عَلَىٰ رَجُلٍ مِّنَ الْقَرْيَتَيْنِ عَظِيمٍ۝
The disbelievers said; And this is an Ayah(آية) in Qur'an.
Why wasn't this Qur'an revealed, on one of the great men of the two towns?
And they were referring to Makkah(مكه); and the At-Taif(طائف).
And one of these men, who the Kuffar(كفّار), suggested as a candidate for Prophethood.
Because some of them were protesting the fact that Muhammad ﷺ was a Rasool(رسول).
واللَّهُ أَعْلَمُ حَيْثُ يَجْعَلُ رِسَالَتَهُ ۗ
Allahعزَوجلَ says; Allah knows best, where to have prophethood.
Anyway, one of these candidates, one of the men, whom the Kuffar(كفّار) suggested, was Urwa Bin Masood As-Saqafe(عروه بن مسعودالثَقفى ) who was from At-Taif(الطَائف).
Years later, the non-believers of Makkah(مكه), would send Urwa Bin Masood As-Saqafe(عروه بن مسعودالثَقفى ) on a mission as an envoy,
to meet with Muhammad(صلي الله عليه وسلم), to negotiate with him a peace agreement; the truce,
which was known as Sulah Hudaybiyah(صلح حديبيه).
Even though he was not successful in reaching an agreement.
The agreement was reached with a later envoy, who was Sohail Ibn Amr(سہیل بن عمرو)
but Urwa Bin Masood(عروه بن مسعود ); he visited Rasool Ullah(صلي الله عليه وسلم ).
He visited the Muslim camp that was set in Hudaybiya(حديبيه); south of Makkah(مكه), a days travel.
And Urwa Bin Masood(عروه بن مسعود) came into a different world.
Urwa Bin Masood رضي الله عنه came in to meet Rasool Allah ﷺ, and he saw with his eyes, things that amazed him.
When Rasool Allah ﷺ would make Wudhu(وضو), the Sahabah(صحابہ) would jump to grab the water that would drop off his body,
in order to rub it, on their faces and hands, to get the blessings from the Rasool Allah ﷺ.
When a hair would fall, they would jump to take it.
When he would give them an order, they would rush to fulfill it.
Subhan-Allah(سبحان الله)! when Urwa Bin Masood(عروه بن مسعود) went back to Makkah(مكه),
by the way probably something worth mentioning, is that
when Urwa Bin Masood(عروه بن مسعود) was talking to Rasool Allah ﷺ;
he wanted to extend his hand and hold the beard of Rasool Ullah صلوت الله وسلم عليه.
So someone standing on top of Rasool Ullah ﷺ next to him; guarding him.
Because sitting down and there was this man, covered in armor from head to toe only the only his eyes could be seen.
This man, whenever Urwa Bin Masood(عروه بن مسعود) would extend his hand forward to hold to the beard of Rasool Allah ﷺ;
so Urwa Bin Masood(عروه بن مسعود) would extend his hand to hold on to the beard of Rasool Ullah ﷺ;
and this man standing next to Rasool Ullah ﷺ, and would strike him with the butt of his sword and tell him;
Pull your hand away before it doesn't come back to you.
So Urwa Bin Masood(عروه بن مسعود) said; I think that this man is the most wicked among you and the most rough.
Who is he?
Rasool Ullah ﷺ smiled and said;
This is your nephew Al-Mughira Bin Shoba(المغيره بن شعبه),
this was the nephew of the Urwa Bin Masood(عروه بن مسعود).
Now, because he was Muslim, he was so devoted to the protection of Rasool Ullah ﷺ,
that he would not even allow his uncle to extend his hand, and touch the beard of Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
Urwa(عروہ) obviously was shocked by this.
And brothers and sisters! you might hear me say this again and again
whenever we talk about those stories, transport yourself to their society, put yourself in their shoes,
and try to think the way they used to think, and try to understand the circumstances that's around you,
this was a tribal society with the tribe and family ties were everything.
And Urwa Bin Masood(عروه بن مسعود) obviously would be quite in a shock state,
to see how Islam has changed his own nephew and Al-Mughira Bin Shoba(المغيره بن شعبه), and how he was, now dealing with him.
Urwa Bin Masood(عروه بن مسعود) went back to Quraish(قریش) and told them;
Oh, people of Quraish(قريش)! I have visited the kings of the world,
and I had audiences, with ceasor and with Kisra(كسرى), the Persian emperor and with the niggas(نجاشی).
And I have never seen the followers of a king, so devoted to their leader, like the Sahaba(صحابه), in their devotion to Muhammad ﷺ.
And I have never seen any obedience among the followers of the king,
like I have seen with the Sahaba(صحابه) with Muhammad ﷺ.
Whenever he would give them a command, they would rush to do it.
And whenever he would speak, they would be silent as if birds are on their heads.
And whenever he would give them a command, they would rush to fulfill it.
And whenever he would make Wudhu(وضو), they would rush to get the droplets of water falling off his body.
Whenever a hair would fall from him, they would take it, and fight to get it.
So, oh people of Quraish(قريش)! Muhammad ﷺ has given you an offer accept it,
because I don't think that his followers will ever give him up.
This was the impression that the disbelievers would get, when they would see the Muslims;
that they would never give him up,
that they would never betray him,
that they would never leave him,
that they would fight until the last man for his protection.
But times are different.
Dear brothers and sisters! This was in the time of Rasool Ullah ﷺ, and this was the shahadah(شهاده); the witness of Urwa Bin Masood(عروه بن مسعود).
Few days ago, the book of Allahعزَوجلَ was used as target practice by a US soldier.
And where did this happen?
It happened in a Muslim country, in the heart of the Muslim world.
And what happened?
The response from the Muslim world was mute.
Earlier, when the Danish cartoon controversy happened, the Muslim world was on fire.
But then with the Swedish cartoon, thing occurred, which was much worse, the reaction was less,
and now we see that the reaction is less,
and so Brothers and Sisters! Our enemies have successfully desensitized us.
It happened the first time everybody was thinking about it, condemning it, concerned about it.
And then slowly and slowly, we get used to this.
And now horrendous things happen, blasphemy to the greatest extent.
And what is the reaction?
Very little.
So, brothers and sisters! Let's, go back and see how things were then?
Because that is what will revive our spirit, and that is the way that we should follow the way of the Sahabaرضى الله عنه.
Kaab Bin Ashraf (كعب بن اشرف) was a Jewish leader, and he was a very eloquent poet.
When the news was carried to Madinah(مدينه), of the victory of the Muslims in battle of Badr(بدر),
when Kaab Bin Ashraf (كعب بن اشرف) heard of that news he said;
ان كان هذا حقى فانَا باطن الارض خيرلنا من ظاهرھا
If this news is true, then being under the earth is better for us than being on top of it; meaning it's better for us to die.
What good is there in living, after the Kuffar(کفار) of Quraish(قريش) have been defeated,
and he started making poems, in which he would lament the loss of Mushrikeen(مشركين), and he would also speak against the Rasool Ullah(ﷺ) and the Muslims.
And then he went on to Makkah(مكه) to present to them his poetry, and to also join them in their losses.
And he went further; He started mentioning Muslim women in this poetry, so Rasool Ullah(ﷺ)  said;
من لكعب بن الاشرف , فإنه قد آذى الله ورسوله
Who will take care of Kaab Bin Ashraf (كعب بن اشرف) because he has harmed Allah and His Messenger.
Muhammad Bin Muslimah رضي الله عنه one of Al-Ansar(الانصار); from the tribe of Aous(أوس), he said!
انا لہ یا رسول اللہ
I will do so, Oh Messenger of Allah! Do you want me to kill him?
أتريد ان اقتلک؟
قال؛ نعم
Rasool Ullah ﷺ said; Yes
Muhammad Bin Muslimah( محمد بن مسلمه) now, he has given a promise.
He has given his word that he would kill Kaab Bin Ashraf (كعب بن اشرف ).
Now he went back home and he started thinking about this, and it seemed to be quite a difficult thing.
Kaab Bin Ashraf (كعب بن اشرف ) is living in a fortress.
He is living in a Jewish area, surrounded by his supporters.
So it's a very, very difficult thing to do, and he became quite concerned about this.
And his concern prevented him from eating and drinking, except for that that would make him survive.
For three days, he would barely eat or drink anything.
That news reached to Rasool Ullah ﷺ, so Rasool Ullah ﷺ called him in and said;
What's wrong with you?
Muhammad Bin Muslimah( محمد بن مسلمه), is it true that you have stopped eating and drinking?
Muhammad Bin Muslimah( محمدبن مسلمه) said; Yes.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ told him why?
He said, I have promised you something, and I wonder whether I would be successful and able to fulfill it.
Rasool Ullah(ﷺ) told him;
انَما عليك الجھد
All what you have to do is do your effort and leave the rest of Allahعزَوجلَ.
We want to stop here for a moment, dear brothers and sisters!
And we want to look at the devotion, and the zeal; that the of the Sahaba(صحابه رضي الله عنهم) had.
He was so concerned about the situation, he couldn't eat or drink, he wasn't able to carry on as usual.
Life doesn't goes on as usual, for him it was a very serious thing,
and he has promised and given his word, and now he is concerned, whether he would be able to fulfill it or not.
Until Rasool Ullah ﷺ told him; You do your part and leave the rest on Allah.
Then he was comfortable and was able to go back to eating and drinking.
How concerned are you?
How concerned are we, when it comes to the honor of Rasool Ullah ﷺ, when it comes to the honor of Islam, when it comes to the honor of the book of Allahعزَوجل.
How serious do we take it.
Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه), for three days, he was thinking day and night about his promise.
We want the spirit of the Sahaba(صحابه).
Muhammad Bin Muslimahرضي الله عنه said; Oh messenger of Allah! Then you're going to have to allow me to speak against you as a part of a plan.
That we're going to have to speak about you in a negative terms.
Rasool Ullah صلي الله عليه وسلم said;
Say whatever you want.
Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمد بن مسلمه) and a small group of Al-Ansar(الانصار) all from his tribe Al-Ous(الاؤس).
They went to visit Kaab Bin Ashraf (كعب بن اشرف) first, to set up the trap for him.
So they went to him, and Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه) was with Abu Naila(ابو نائلہ) one of the men who were with Muhammad(محمد).
Abu Naila(ابو نائلہ) was mentioned that he was a brother in Radhaa(رضاعی), a brother of  Kaab Bin Ashraf (كعب بن اشرف ).
They told Kaab(كعب);
انّ هذاالرّجلماهوالّابلاءٌمن البلاء
This man has been a test, from Allah to us, he has been a problem, he's a disaster, they're referring to Muhammad ﷺ.
And the Arabs have, all fought us and taken us as enemies because of him.
Kaab(كعب) told him; I already told you so, and you're going to see even worse times.
Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه) said; Well, we want to wait and see how all of this will end.
He's now trying to build report with him.
And then he said; So Kaab(كعب) our financial situation has deteriorated because of this man.
We want to borrow from you some barley, and we want to leave you a guarantee.
He said; Well, leave me your children.
They said; Subhan-Allah(سبحان الله)! We leave you, our children,
and then for the rest of their lives, people will tell them that that your parents, have put you in, for a small amount of barley,
and will be shame on them for the rest of their lives.
He said; Then you leave with me your women.
He said; How can we leave our women with you; and you are the most handsome man.
But we will bring with us, and leave with you our weapons.
He said; Fine.
Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه) wants to set him up, so that next time when they bring their weapons with them, you would not be suspicious.
So they set an appointment, and they came back to him, and they called him late at night, at right time.
They called him late at night, and his wife told him, I can smell blood in his voice.
He said; Don't worry; This is Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه) my friend, and it is my brother Abu Naila(ابو نائلہ)
It shows that there was some good relationship between them.
There was friendship from the time of Jahiliyah(جاھلیۃ).
And don't worry about it.
So he went down to meet them.
Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه) set up a sign with his companions.
He told them, when you see me, grab his head, then tear him apart with your sword.
This was the sign.
So Kaab(كعب) came down, and they told them, how about we go walking to Shaib AL-Ajooz(شعب العجوز), and we spend our night over there talking.
He said; Fine.
So they were able to drag him away from his fortress, because he used to live, in a strong fortress.
So now they pulled him away to this far away place, called Shaib AL-Ajooz(شعب العجوز), and when they reached there,
Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه) told Kaab(كعب);
Wow, this smell that is coming from you, is so beautiful.
He had a musk or some other perfume in his hair.
Can I smell it?
He said; Yes, go ahead.
So Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه), put his hand in his head and then pulled it towards him and smelted it; He said, it's wonderful.
This was a test, trial.
The next time, he told him, Can you let me smell it again?
He said; Yes, go ahead.
He grabbed him, and the sword started striking at Kaab Bin Ashraf (كعب بن اشرف), but they were not sufficient to kill him, and he screamed for help.
And now suddenly, Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه) said; all of the fortresses were lit up in a moment.
So Muhammad(محمد) said; I remembered that I had a dagger with me,
so I pulled it out, and I stuck it in his stomach, and pulled it down, until it hit the pubic bone, and then we left.
This is how Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه) and his men from Al-Ous(الاؤس) dealt with the one, who cursed Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) mentions this story in his book, As-Sarim Al-Maslool Ala Shatim Ar-Rasool(الصارم المسلول على شاتم الرسول);
The Drawn Sword And The One Who Curses The Messenger.
And he mentions a few things, we'll go through them.
First of all, he brings a narration from Al-Waqidi(الواقعدى).
Al-Waqidi(الواقعدى); one of the scholars of Seerah(سيرة).
Al-Waqidi(الواقعدى), is talking about the consequences of what happened.
This was a very powerful special operation, and the consequences of it, were great.
It sent a ripple among the Jewish community and the disbelieving community that was surrounding Madina.
So Al-Waqidi(الواقعدى) said;
قال ففزعت يهود ومن معها من المشركين فجاؤا إلى النبيﷺ حين اصبحوا فقالوا قد طرق صاحبنا الليلة
وهو سيد من ساداتنا قتل غيلة بلا جرم ولا حدث علمناه
He said the Jews mobilized along with the Mushrikeen(مشركين), and they came to Rasool Ullah ﷺ in the morning, and they said;
Our man has been killed tonight, and he is one of our noble men and leaders.
He was assassinated, they said;
قتل غيله
And Gheela(غيله) means assassination; and the word also has some negative connotations,
because it means that the person was killed and taken by surprise; he didn't know about it.
It wasn't a Duel, It wasn't a one on one.
He was killed in secret without him knowing about it.
They said; he was assassinated;
بلا جرم ولا حدث علمناه
Without committing any crime.
Why was Kaab Ibn Ashraf(كعب ابن اشرف ) killed?
That was their question put to Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
Because there was an agreement, there was an agreement between Rasool Ullah ﷺ and all of the Yahood(يهود) that's well known in Seerah(سيرة).
That Rasool Ullah(ﷺ), when he came to Madinah(مدينه), he had the peace agreement with all of the Yahood(یھود)
and now Kaab Bin Ashraf (كعب بن اشرف) was killed.
Why?
How come that happened?
What does Rasool Ullah ﷺ say?
فقال رسول الله
إنه لوقركما قرغيره ممن هوعلى مثل رأيه ما اغتيل، ولكنه نال مناالأذى،
وهجانا بالشعر، ولم يفعل هذاأحد منكم إلا كان له السيف
Rasool Ullah ﷺ said;
If he had calmed down, like others who follow his opinion, or the same opinion as his; have calmed down.
He wouldn't have been assassinated, but he has harmed us, and he has defamed us with his poetry.
And none of you would do this, except we would deal with him with the sword.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ is saying; there are many, who have in their hearts the same belief as Kaab Bin Ashraf (كعب بن اشرف).
He wasn't killed because of that.
So he wasn't killed because of this belief.
He wasn't killed because he hated Rasool Ullah.
He wasn't killed because he hated the Muslims.
No!
There are many people who have that disease in their hearts, and we have left them alone.
لو قر كما قر غيره
If he had calmed down, like other people calmed down, we wouldn't have assassinated him.
But he spoke against us, he spoke against me, and he defamed me with his poetry.
And then he made it clear to the Yahood(يهود),
if any one of you, You! Al-Yahood(اليهود ) Or the Mushrikeen(مشركين),
if any one of you, try to defame me through your words, this will be the way we deal with you.
There's nothing between us and you except the sword.
There will be no dialog, there will be no forgiveness,
there will be no building of bridges,
there will be no attempts of reconciliation,
there will be only be the sword between me and you.
And he made it very clear,
and then he called them to come, and sign a document in which they all state their agreement, that they will not speak against him.
Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) says;
وذلك يضل على ان اذى الله ورسوله علّة لندب المسلمين الى قتل من يفعل ذلك من المعاهدين
And this is evidence that harming Allah and His Messenger, is a reason to encourage Muslims to kill whoever does that,
even if they have a contract with the Muslims and Al-Muahideen(معاهدين) even if there's a covenant.
Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) in his book, responds to some of the arguments and doubts, that were placed against this Hukkum(حكم).
So he uses this story as an evidence to refute those arguments.
And then he said;
وايذ فقد قدّمنا فى حديث جابر؛ ان اوّل ما نقذ به العهدقصيدته الّتى انشأهابعد رجوع الى المدينه يهجو بها رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم وان رسول الله
عند ما هجاه بهذ قصيده نضب الى قتله وهذا وحده دليل على انه انما نقذ العهد بالهجاء، لا بدہح الی مکہ
Some people try to twist the meaning of this hadith(حديث)
and say that Kaab(كعب) was killed because of him, encouraging the disbelievers to fight against Muhammad ﷺ and not because of his words.
Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) says; No, he was killed because of his poetry, which was even before he set out to go to Makkah(مكه),
so it had nothing to do with him going to Makkah(مكه), and encouraging them to fight the Muslims.
It was specifically because of his poetry.
And then he says;
أن جميع ما أتاه ابن الأشرف إنما هو أذى باللسان،
فإن مرثیۃ لقتلى المشركين وتحضيضه وسبه وحجائہ وطعنه في دين الإسلام وتفضيله دين الكفار عليه كله قول باللسان
ولم يعمل عملا فيه محاربة وابن الأشرف لم يوجد منه إلا أذى باللسان فقط،
فهو حجة على من نازع في هذه المسائل،فثبت أن أذى الله ورسوله بالهجاء ونحوه لا يحقن معه الدم بالأمان
He said; everything that Ibn Al-Ashraf(ابن الاشرف) did, was harmed by the tongue, his lamenting of the guilt of the disbelievers.
And his encouraging them to fight,
and his cursing and his defamation, and his putting down of the religion of Islam
and preferring the religion of the disbelievers.
All of this, were words by the tongue, and he did not do anything.
These are the words of Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه).
He did not do anything, that included physical fighting of the Muslim.
And Ibn Al-Ashraf(ابن الاشرف); all what he did was harm the Muslims with his tongue.
And this is(حجه), and this is an evidence against anyone who argue in these issues.
And it is clear, that the harming of Allah and his messenger by poetry, and defamation
the blood of such a person is not protected by any means.
This is the story of Kaab Bin Ashraf (كعب بن اشرف).
Next story,
This was something that Ous(الاؤس) did.
And the son of Kaab Bin Malik(كعب بن مالك), he said;
that Al-Ous(الاؤس) Al-Khazraj(الحزرج), used to compete with each other in front of Rasool Ullah(ﷺ) like two Stalins,
whenever one of them do something to please Rasool Ullah, the other one want to out do them.
Their competition was not on degrees, was not on wealth, was not who would have a better house,
was not on, who would marry a more beautiful wife, was not on who owes a better car.
Their competition was who would please Rasool Ullah ﷺ more.
So now Khazraj(حزرج) came to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
They had a meeting before, and they said;
Listen Al-Ous(الاؤس); they succeeded in assassinating, one of the enemies of Rasool Ullah.
We gonna have to do the same.
So who's the worst, after Kaab Bin Ashraf(كعب بن اشرف ); they said Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع).
They presented their plans to Rasool Ullah ﷺ and said; we want to do the same with Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع).
Rasool Ullah ﷺ told them to go ahead, he approved the plan, and told them to go ahead with it.
They went to assassinate Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع).
I will summarize the story.
You could go back to it, if you want In the books of Seerah(سيرة), the details of the story are not pertinent here.
We just want to use it as an evidence for what we are talking about.
Abdullah Bin Ateeq(عبدالله بن عتيق) was successful in entering into the fortress.
He used a trick to get inside the fortress, and then he made it into the bedroom of Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع),
because he was able to get hold of the keys.
And now he could not see Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع), because it was complete darkness, and it was very late at night.
So what did he do?
Well, he said Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع).!!
He called out for Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع), quite a striking thing to do.
It takes a lot of courage, to call somebody whom you're attacking, when you're inside his bedroom, and it's total darkness.
He just straight ahead, called him Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع); Where are you?
So Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع) responded to the sound.
Abdullah Bin Ateeq(عبدالله بن عتيق) said, so I struck towards the direction of the sound.
I hit him, but I did not kill him, and he yelled out for help.
Now, Abdullah Bin Ateeq(عبدالله بن عتيق); Ma sha Allah(ماشاءالله); was very good in thinking on his feet.
He immediately withdrew, and then he came back, and he changed his voice, pretending to be help.
And he said; What do you need Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع) ?
Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع) said; Woe unto your mother; There's somebody in here, trying to kill me.
So he said; I attacked the source of the voice again, but I could not kill him.
So he called for help again.
He retreated another time came in, changing his voice.
He said this time; Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع) was already lying on his back, because he has been struck twice.
So Abdullah Bin Ateeq(عبدالله بن عتيق) said; I thrust my sword into his stomach, and I pushed it in, until I heard the bone crack.
The backbone cracking means; that he has tore apart the spinal cord, and that's the end of him.
Abdullah Bin Ateeq(عبدالله بن عتيق); he retreated, and he made it down a staircase or a ladder.
And he said; out of confusion, I thought that I have finished the staircase, but there was one step left.
So I fell down and broke my leg.
I then went to my companions and told him that I've killed him,
but I want to make sure, so I'm going to wait here, you go and deliver the news to Rasool Ullah ﷺ;
I'm going to wait here until I hear the announcement.
I mean look at how they wanted to perfect work.
He broke his leg, and he broke the spine of the man, he still wants to wait behind and make sure that the job is done.
In all that pain, he still wants to wait behind.
In Fajar(فجر) time the news broke that Abu Rafa'h Tajir-Il-Hijaz(ابو رافع تاجر الحجاز) was killed.
What did Abdullah Bin Ateeq(عبدالله بن عتيق) say?
He said; We condemn this act of violence.
This man shouldn't have been touched with any harm, and this is an un Islamic act to do,
what did he say?
What did Abdullah Bin Ateeq(عبدالله بن عتيق) say?
Abdullah Bin Ateeq(عبدالله بن عتيق) said;
والذى نفسى بيده ما سمعت كلمات احلا على اذنيه منها
He said; When I heard the news, that Abu Rafa'h(ابو رافع) was killed, when I heard the announcement,
I swear there were no words sweeter to my ears than these words, I never heard in my life; words that are sweeter than those.
This is what Abdullah Bin Ateeq(عبدالله بن عتيق) said.
This is how they love the Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
And he rushed towards Madinah(مدينه) and when Rasool Ullah ﷺ saw him, what did he say?
He said;
افلح الوجه
May your face space be successful.
They responded back to Rasool Ullah and told him;
وافلح وجهك يارسول الله
May your face be successful.
They were happy, and Rasool Ullah ﷺ was happy.
Number three!
When Rasool Ullah ﷺ opened Makkah(مكه).
Rasool Ullah ﷺ wanted this to be a non violent conqueror of the holy town.
He wanted it to be a procession of peace.
He didn't want any bloodshed.
And he entered with humility, making Sujood(سجود) to Allahعزَوجلَ; and thanking him.
There was no parade, there was no singing, there was no bloodshed and killing.
There was peace;
اذهبوا فأنتم الطلقاء
Go you are free.
However, there was a blacklist.
This was a list of names that were to be killed, even if you have found them hanging to the cloths of Al-Kabah(الكعبه).
This is a saying that the Arabs(عرب) had, the holiest place in the world was Makkah(مكه),
and the holiest of the holy was Al haram(الحرم).
And if somebody is touching the cloth of Al-Kabah(الكعبه) and hanging to it, leave him alone.
That was even the rule among the Mushrikeen(مشركين ) in the time of Jahiliyah(جاهليۃ).
Rasool Ullah(ﷺ) said;
فاقتلوهم وان كانوامعلقين على أستار الكعبة
Kill them, even if you see them hanging to the cloth of Al-Kabah(الكعبه).
Who were they?
This list included some names.
Among these names was a man called, Abdullah Bin Khatal(عبدالله بن خطل);
and to his two slave singing girls and Sarah Mawlaat Abi Lahab(سارہ مولات ابى لهب);
Who were these?
Abdullah Bin Khatal(عبدالله بن خطل) is a man; he had these two slave girls, who used to sing, against Rasool Ullah ﷺ;
and they would hold concerts in Makkah(مكه), singing against Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
So his two slave girls were on that list, along with another slave girl that belonged to Abu Lahab(ابو لهب).
Now; let's look at this issue.
First of all; with Abdullah Bin Khatal(عبدالله بن خطل) he actually was hanging to the cloth of Al-Kabah(الكعبه), and a companion rushed towards him and killed him.
But let's look at, the interesting case of these three women.
Number one; dear brothers and sisters! you all know, that women are not to be killed.
رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم نهى عن قتل النّساء
Rasool Ullah ﷺ was prohibited the killing of women.
And these were specifically mentioned in this list to be killed.
That's number one.
We know that women; if they join in the fighting against Muslims, they can be killed.
But these women were not fighting, and did not participate in any fighting.
In fact; they were in a state of complete surrender.
That's number two.
Number three; Rasool Ullah ﷺ has given peace and security to all the people of Makkah(مكه)
and he singled them out.
Then an added issue is that they were not free women, but they were slaves.
And the issue of free will plays an important part in the rules, and legislations of punishment in Islam,
because the slave doesn't have free will, the punishments are reduced.
And these women, were not free in choosing to sing against Rasool Ullah(ﷺ);
but they were ordered to do so by their masters; Abu Lahab(ابو لهب) and Abdullah Bin Khatal(عبدالله بن خطل).
And yet they were singled out and told to be killed.
Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) talks about this, is a clear and strong evidence, that the greatest crime of all is blasphemy against Rasool Ullah ﷺ,
because with all of these factors, the fact that he gave security to the people of  Makkah(مكه),
and the fact that they are women, and the fact that they did not fight, and the fact that they were slaves,
nevertheless they were still singled out for capital punishment, tells you that this is a great crime.
فعلم ان السّب من اغلب المؤجبات القتل
Then we have another man, who was on this blacklist.
His name Al-Hawarith Bin Naqidh(الحويرث بن نقيذ); He used to also harm Rasool Ullah ﷺ with his tongue, so he went into hiding.
He was hiding in his house, and then Ali Bin Abi Talib(على بن ابى طالب) came to his house asking about him.
So they said he's not here; he left to Al-Badia(الباديه); to outside Makkah(مكه).
And they told Al hawarith(الحويرث); That Ali Bin Abi Talib(على بن ابى طالب) came looking for you,
so Ali(على) went to hide behind his house,
and Al hawaris(الحويرث) wanted to run away from his house to another house.
Ali Bin Abi Talib(على بن ابى طالب) cut him off and killed him.
Another example is Kaab Ibn Zuhair(كعب ابن زوهير).
Kaab Ibn Zuhair(كعب ابن زوهير) was a poet; His brother was a poet, and his father was one of the greatest poets.
He was one of the ones, who had Al-Muallaqat(المعلّقات);
The Arabs(عرب) used to honor the best pieces of poetry by hanging them on Al-Kabah(الكعبه).
This was to express the beauty of this piece of work.
And the father of kaab(كعب), Zuhair Bin Abi Salma(زوهير بن ابی سلمه) was one of these, who had his poems hanging on Al-Kabah(الكعبه).
His son Kaab(كعب) was a poet, and also Bujair(بجير) was a poet.
But Bujair(بجير) was a Muslim, and Kaab(كعب) was a non Muslim, and he used to make poetry against Rasool Ullah.
So when the Muslims entered into Makkah(مكه), Bujair(بجير) wrote a letter to his to his brother,
and he told him that Rasool Ullah ﷺ is killing the men of Makkah(مكه), who had poetry against him,
and they were not from Makkah(مكه).
So he was he was warning him.
So Kaab(كعب) wasn't in Makkah(مكه), but his brother sent him a letter for forehand warning him,
and he told him that, listen; Rasool Ullah ﷺ is killing all of the people who spoke against him.
And he told him that the ones who are left, like Abdullah Bin Zabari(عبدالله بن زبعرى)  and Hubayra Bin Abi Wahab(هبيره بن ابى وهب);
they are trying to flee and run away because Rasool Ullah ﷺ has issued his orders, to kill anybody who speaks against him.
So this is another example of the greatness of this crime.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ; who was merciful, who would forgive his enemies.
But with this particular crime, things were different.
And then we have the story of Uqbah Bin Abi Mueet(عقبه بن ابى معيط) and Nazar Bin Haris(نذر بن حارث).
In the battle of Badar(بدر); there were 70 prisoners of war from the disbelievers of Quraish(قريش).
Rasool Ullah ﷺ asked that they be presented to him.
So Rasool Ullah ﷺ would look at them one by one.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ was staring at Nazar Bin Haris(نذر بن حارث);
and Nazar Bin Haris(نذر بن حارث) looked into the eyes of Rasool Ullah ﷺ and saw something.
So he told the man next to him.
He said; Listen, I'm going to be killed.
I can see death in the eyes of Rasool Ullah.
The man told him, No, you're just exaggerating, You're too afraid; You're just terrified.
He said, No, I'm telling you, I saw death in the eyes of Rasool Ullah ﷺ
and then another Nazar Bin Haris(نذر بن حارث); he called Musab Bin Umair(مصعب بن عمير), who was his relative.
And he told him, Listen; Go to Rasool Ullah ﷺ and tell him to treat me like everybody else.
Treat me like a man from my people.
If he's going to kill them; then let him kill me, if he is going to forgive them; Let him forgive me.
Musab Bin Umair(مصعب بن عمير) told him you are the one who said; what you have said about Rasool Ullah ﷺ;
and you are the one, who spoke against the book of Allah.
Nazar Bin Haris(نذر بن حارث); he is the one, who used to hold the Halaqah(حلقہ) next to Rasool Ullah ﷺ to compete with him.
He traveled to Persia to learn stories, and then he came back and told the disbelievers.
He told them, listen; Muhammad ﷺ is telling you tales.
I have some better tales to tell you, Come and listen to me.
He told him; Please, Musab(مصعب), speak to Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
He said; Aren't you the one, who used to torture his companions?
Rasool Ullah ﷺ called Nazar Bin Haris(نذر بن حارث) and told Ali Bin Abi Talib(على بن ابى طالب)  to execute him.
He was singled out.
And then after that, now they're traveling back, so they reached a particular area, he executed Nazar Bin Haris(نذر بن حارث)
and then when they traveled a little further, he summoned Uqbah Bin Abi Mueet(عقبه بن ابى معيط) for execution.
Uqbah(عقبه) said;
يا ويلي علام أقتل يا قريش من بين من ههنا؟
Woe unto me! why am I singled out for execution?
All of the men here with me are your enemies.
All of the men here with me have fought you.
All of the men here with me are from Quraish(قريش ); my tribe.
Why are you single me out?
Rasool Ullah(ﷺ) said;
لعداوتك لله ورسوله
Because of your animosity towards Allah and His messenger.
قال؛ يا محمد منك أفضل فاجعلني كرجل من قومي إن قتلتهم قتلتني وإن مننت عليهم مننت علي
وإن أخذت منهم الفداء كنت كأحدهم
He said; Oh Muhammad(محمد)! Treat me as one of my people;
If you execute them, execute me.
If you free them, free me, If you take compensation for their freedom, then take what you want from me.
And then he said; Oh Muhammad(محمد), who will take care of my children.
Rasool Ullahﷺ said; An-Naar(النار); Hellfire.
قدمه يا عاصم فاضرب عنقه،
فقدمه عاصم فضرب عنقه
Take him O Asim(عاصم) and cut off his head.
And than Rasool Ullah(ﷺ) said;
"بئس الرجل كنت والله ما علمت كافرا بالله وبكتابه وبرسوله
مؤذيا لنبيه فأحمد الله الذي هو قتلك وأقر عيني منك
What an evil man you were.
I don't know of a man who was a disbeliever in Allah; and his book and his messenger like you and you harmed the Prophet of Allah.
So I praise Allah; the One, Who killed you and the One, Who has pleased my eyes by seeing you die.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ treated these people differently; and it's very clear.
An(عن) Ibn Abbas رضي الله عنه he said; There was a blind man, and he had Umm-Walad(ام ولد).
Umm-Walad(ام ولد) is a bonded woman; whom her master has children with, so then she is called Ummu Walad(ام ولد).
There are special rules that apply to her.
So he had this Umm-Walad(ام ولد), and he had two children from her,
but she used to curse Rasool Ullah ﷺ, and he would warn her to stop, but she wouldn't stop.
One night, she was carrying on with cursing Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
So he took a dagger and he put it in her stomach, and he pressed it in and he killed her.
In the morning, the news reached to Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
So Rasool Ullah ﷺ gathered the people and said;
انشل الله رجلا فعل ما فعل لى عليه حق الّا قام
I ask you in the Name of Allah; whoever did that to stand up.
So the blind man stood up, and he came walking towards Rasool Ullah ﷺ,
حتى قعد بين يدى النّبى صلى الله عليه وسلم
Until he sat in front of Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
So he said;
يا رسول الله اناصاحبھا
Oh Messenger of Allah! I am the one who did that.
She used to curse you, and I would tell her to stop, and she wouldn't stop.
And I have from her two children, like pearls.
وكا نت بى رفيقه
And she was very kind with me, but last night, she started cursing you.
So I took a dagger and I stuck it in her and killed her.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ said;
الی فاشهدوا انّ دمها حدر
Bear witness that her blood is invalidated.
Meaning there is no compensation and for her and there is no punishment for the one, who killed her.
And I want you to think about the words of this man.
He has from her children, and he described them as pearls,
and he said;
وكا نت بى رفيقا
She was very kind with me.
And this is a blind man; who needed the help of such a kind woman, who was very nice with him.
Because we should love Rasool Ullah ﷺ more than we love ourselves.
And we should love Rasool Ullah ﷺ more than we love our families, and we should love him more than anything in this world.
This is why I did what I did.
It was for your sake, and this is how every Muslim should be, when it comes to the issue of Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
And Rasool Ullah ﷺ proved what he did and said;
على فاشهدوا انّ دمه حدر
And there is another situation similar to this; that happened, where a man killed his wife.
What did Rasool Ullah ﷺ say about it?
Did he send him to be punished?
He said;
لا ينتطح فيها عنزان
No two goats shall butt heads about it.
And we'll talk about the story.
And it's mentioned by Al-Waqidi(الواقعدى).
This woman, her name was Asma Bint Marwan(اسما بنت مروان).
Sorry; I said it was the man killed his wife; No.
It's a man from her tribe.
Her name is Asma Bint Marwan(اسما بنت مروان), and she was from Al-Ansar(الانصار ),
but she used to speak against Rasool Ullah ﷺ, and speak against Islam.
And she would try to cause Fitna(فتنه) among the people.
She would tell them that this man doesn't belong to our tribe.
How come; we are hosting him and causing ourselves all of this trouble.?
How come; we're giving him safe haven to stay among us?
Just drive him out, because the Ansar(انصار), they suffered a lot because of the Hijra(هجری) of Rasool Ullah ﷺ,
and financially they suffered.
Many of them were killed.
Their city was besieged, but they were doing it for the sake of Allahعزَوجلَ;
and that's why they were called Ansar(انصار), the ones who gave victory to Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
And she was a poet, she was a good poet.
Umair Bin Adi(عمير بن عدي) from her family, he said;
اللهم إن لك عليّ نذراً لئن رددت رسول الله ﷺ إلى المدينة لأقتلنّها
He said; In the name of Allah, I make this vow, that if Rasool Ullah ﷺ returns to Madinah(مدينه), I'm going to kill her.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ at that time was in Badar(بدر).
When Rasool Ullah ﷺ returned, Umair Bin Adi(عمير بن عدي) went to her, in the middle of the night,
and he went straight to her room, and she was surrounded by her children, and they were asleep,
and one of them was breast feeding from her.
And this man was blind, he touched around, and we saw that she was holding this child.
So he held the child with his hands and put the child next to her.
And then he took his sword and placed it, in her chest.
And then he went and prayed Fajar(فجر) with Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
So when Rasool Ullah finished Salah(صلاه), he looked at Umair(عمير) and told him;
Did you kill the daughter of Marwan(مروان)?
He said; Yes.
I sacrifice my father for you; O Messenger of Allah.
Now Umair(عمير) was worried that he might have done something wrong, and he should have sought the permission of Rasool Ullah(ﷺ).
Rasool Ullah was Wali Ul-Amr(ولى الامر); so he should seek his permission.
So he asked Rasool Ullah.
هل علي في ذلك شيء يارسول الله؟
Is there anything wrong, in what I did; O messenger of Allah!
What did Rasool Ullah(ﷺ) say?
He said; You should have sought my permission.
He told them;
لا ينتطح فيها عنزان
No two goats shall butt heads about her.
Meaning; this issue is so clear, no two goats will even have a difference of opinion.
Not even the animals will have difference opinion on this.
And now Subhan-Allah(سبحان الله ); we find that there is a difference of opinion on this.
Rasool Ullah is saying that even animals should understand this.
It is so straight forward that no two goats shall butt heads about it.
So how come we find that men; intelligent men are butting heads about this issue.
How come there should be any difference of opinion on this issue that is so clear and so straight forward
that it is Ijma(اجماع); a consensus of the scholars, as we will talk about In Sha Allah(ان شاءالله).
And then Umair(عمير) said; Rasool Ullah ﷺ looked at those around him and said;
إذا أحببتم أن تنظروا إلى رجل نصر الله ورسوله بالغيب،
فانظروا إلى عمير بن عدي
If you want to see a man who has supported, and given victory to Allah and His Messenger, then look at Umair Bin Adi(عمير بن عدي).
Umar Bin Khatab(عمر بن خطاب) said;
انظروا إلى هذا الأعمى الذي تسرى في طاعة الله
Look at this blind man who has went out at night, in obedience of Allahعزَوجلَ.
Rasool Ullah(ﷺ) said;
لا تقل الأعمى، ولكنه البصير
Don't say he's a blind man, because he's a man with very clear vision.
There are many blind men today.
فلما رجع عمير من عند رسول الله ﷺ
Umair(عمیر); he went back, he found the children, along with some tribe members of this woman, burying her.
So they came to him; they said;
Oh, Umair(عمير)! you're the one who killed her.
You know, they walked showing off, threatening him.
They came and said; you're the one who killed her, and these are fighters.
We're talking about the men from Al-Aous(الأوس ), Al-Khazraj(الحزرج), the people, who were born into fighting.
They came to him and they said, Umair(عمير), you're the one who killed our mother.
You're the one who killed her.
He said; Yes, and I challenge you all.
فكيدوني جميعاً ثم لا تنظرون، فوالذي نفسي بيده
لو قلتم بأجمعكم ما قالت لضربتكم بسيفي هذا حتى أموت أو أقتلكم
He said; All of you gathered together, and if any one of you, would say something similar to what she said;
I'm going to fight you all, until either I kill you all or I die.
What were the results of this action?
Could it cause them to be to flee away from Islam?
Because this was soon after the Hijra(هجری) of Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
We talked about, just after the Battle of Badar(بدر).
So not all of the Ansar(انصار) were Muslim at the time, so something like this might have caused the people to turn away from Islam,
and this man was challenging them, and telling them that I'm going to kill you all, if anybody of you try to stand in my face.
But Al-Waqidi(الواقعدى), Actually what did Al-Waqidi(واقعدى) says?
He said;
فيومئذ ظهر الإسلام في بني خطمة،
وكان منهم رجال يستخْفُون بالإسلام خوفاً من قومهم
He said that is when Islam prevailed among these people,
because the ones who were Muslim, then were underground in fear, from their people.
But when they saw the strength of Islam now, they started revealing themselves.
So what can we learn from this story, and this story before that, it's very important issue.
There's a lot of talk, these days about seeking permission from the ruler.
I will ask you this question.
Somebody attacks you at home and wants to kill you.
What did Rasool Ullah ﷺ say?
من قتل دون ماله فهو شهيد، ومن قتل دون نفسه فهو شهيد
If you fight to protect yourself, and if you're killed you're a shahid(شهيد).
And if you fight to protect your wealth, you are shahid(شهيد), right?
I mean; I'm sure all of you know that Hadith(حديث); Okay.
Somebody came attacked you at home, and holding a gun to your head trying to kill you.
And you want to fight back what is known in Fiqah Islamia(فقه اسلاميه) as Dif'a-Is-Saib(دفعۃ الصائب), something very clear.
Do you have to seek permission from the ruler?
The guy is holding a gun to your head, so you pick up the phone and call the presidential palace or the king.
And you have to go through a bunch of secretaries and a lot of red tape,
until you get through to him and then tell him, excuse me! can I please defend myself, there's some body trying to kill me.
Does that make sense?
So if you don't need the permission from the Imam(امام) to defend yourself?
Do you need permission from the Imam(امام) to defend Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
This man who went and killed the woman from bani khatam(بنى ختم), did he seek permission from Rasool Ullah ﷺ?
When Rasool Ullah ﷺ was alive?
No, he didn't.
And the blind man who killed the mother of his children.
Did he seek permission from Rasool Ullah ﷺ before hand?
No, he didn't.
And they did so, and Rasool Ullah ﷺ approved them of what they did.
And he said;
لا ينتطح فيها عنزان
No two goats shall butt heads about it.
So this issue of seeking the permission of the Imam(امام), the status of Rasool Ullah ﷺ much higher than that.
Who is the Imam(امام), to start with to give you permission to defend Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
This is an issue much higher than the status of any ruler.
Brothers and sisters! Keep in mind who we're talking about.?
We're talking about Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
You don't need the permission of anyone, to defend the honor of Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
He is much higher than that.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ is the one whom Allah; and His angels and the believers are making Salah(صلاه) in him.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ is special, he has some special Ahkam(احكام).
He is treated differently.
These rules do not apply to Rasool Ullah ﷺ, this is an issue that must be clear.
Then there's the story of a poet, that belonged to the tribe of Banu Bakr(بنو بكر).
Banu Bakr(بنوبكر) were allies of Quraish(قريش ).
There was a poet among them who would speak against Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
So one man from Khuzaah(خزاعه), and Khuzaah(خزاعه) were Mushrikeen(مشركين).
They were disbelievers, but they were allies of Muhammad ﷺ.
In Sulh-Hal-Hudaybiya(صلح حديبيه); Khuzaah(خزاعه) signed up in alliance with Rasool Ullah.
While Banu Bakr(بنوبكر) signed up an alliance with Quraish(قريش).
So this young man from Khuzaah(خزاعه); he struck the head of this poet.
He didn't kill him, but he hurt him.
And then they went in a delegation to Rasool Ullah ﷺ, they told him about what happened,
فنظر دمه
He said; His blood is spilled; Kill him.
Later on, Makkah(مكه) was opened and Banu Bakr(بنوبكر) became Muslim.
And Nofal Bin Muawiyah(نوفل بن معاويه); he came to Rasool Ullah ﷺ, to talk about the issue of this poet.
Now, who's Nofal Bin Muawiyah(نوفل بن معاويه)?
Nofal Bin Muawiyah(نوفل بن معاويه) is the man who betrayed Rasool Ullah ﷺ and betrayed the Muslims.
And he is the one, who killed the people of Khuzaah(خزاعه) inside Al-Haram(الحرم).
And when his followers from Banu Bakr(بنوبكر) said to him; Fear Allah.
I mean, these are Kuffar(كفار) telling him; Fear Allah.
You're killing people inside Al-Haram(الحرم).
He said; There is no God today, Seek your revenge.
Forget about Allah.
Seek your revenge.
This man; Nofal Bin Muawiyah(نوفل بن معاويه), this kafir, who betrayed Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
And killed Khuzaah(خزاعه), men from Khuzaah(خزاعه) who are the allies of Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
He is the one who came to appeal for this poet.
Whose crime is greater, The crime of Nofal(نوفل), or the crime of the poet?
Nofal(نوفل) what he did was disastrous.
Never Rasool Ullah ﷺ forgave him, and he is the one, who came to appeal, for that poet and he said;
O Rasool Ullah ﷺ the people of Khuzaah(خزاعه) exaggerated the issue, and he wants to be Muslim, and he wants to repent.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ accepted his Taubah(توبہ).
Tayeb(طیب); so I mention to you stories from the early days of Islam.
Let's move on, to what the scholars said.
What have the scholars said about this issue.
Brothers and sisters! Very briefly; I'm going to mention to you statements of Ulama(علماء),
but there are two books that talked about this issue in detail,
and anybody who wants to further elaborate on the issue, I would recommend that you read them.
The first book is the book that I mentioned.
The whole book is written on the subject of blasphemy against Rasool Ullah.
And this is a book by Shaikh Al-Islam(شيخ الاسلام) Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه).
The name of it is As-Sarim Al-Maslool Ala Shatim-Ar-Rasool(الصارم المسلول على شاتم الرسول).
The drawn sword, against the one who curses the messenger.
The other book is Al-Shifa Fee Ahwal Al-Mustafa(الشفاء فی احوال المصطفى); by Qazi Ayyaz(قاضى عياض) a Maliki(مالکی) scholar.
The book talks about Rasool Ullah ﷺ in general,
but then the last part includes a section on blasphemy.
We'll start with what Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) said.
Ibn Taymiyyah says;
من سب النبي ﷺ من مسلم او كافر فانّه يجب قتله
Whoever curses Rasool Ullah ﷺ; a Muslim or a non Muslim, then he must be killed.
And he says;
وهذا مذهب عامة اهل العلم
And this is the opinion of the general body of scholars.
And Ibn Mundhir(ابن منذر) says;
أجمع عوام أهل العلم علی أن حد من سب النبى القتل
It is the consensus of our scholars that the one who curses Rasool Ullah; should be executed.
And this is the opinion of Malik(مالك), Al Laith(الليث), Ahmed(احمد), Ishaq(اسحاق), Al-Shafi(الشافعى) and Al Numan Abu Hanifa(النعمان ابو حنيفه).
He said that the opinion of Al-Ahnaf(الحناف) is that; if a Muslim speaks against Rasool Ullah ﷺ,
then he should be executed, and if a non Muslim, who doesn't have a contract, he should also be executed,
and he only excludes Az-Zimmi(الذّمى), the non believer who is Zimmi(ذمّى) who pays Jizya(جزيه).
And the reasoning of Imam Abu Hanifa(امام ابو حنيفه) is that they are Kuffar(كفّار) to start with.
So the crime of kufr(كفر) is greater than this.
So all of the scholars agree in the situation of the Muslim and the Muhad(محاد),
there's only a difference of opinion, and it's a minority view, with the case Az-Zimmi(الذّمى).
and then Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه); he goes into elaborate details, to also prove that Az-Zimmi(الذّمى) the one who is paying Jizya(جزيه);
when he speaks against Rasool Ullah ﷺ that nullifies His covenant, and therefore he should also be executed.
In Al-Shifa(الشفاء) Qazi Ayyaz(قاضى عياض) says;
مذهب مالك ، وأصحابه أن من قال فيه ﷺ ؛ ما فيه نقص قتل دون استتابة
It is The mazhab(مذهب) of Malik(مالك); that whoever says something that belittles Rasool Ullah ﷺ ,
he should be executed without any warning.
And Ibn Attab(ابن عتاب) says;
الكتاب و السنة موجبان أن من قصد النبي صلى الله عليه و سلم بأذى أو نقص ،
معرضاً أو مصرحاً ، و إن قل ـ فقتله واجب
Ibn Attab(ابن عتاب) says; that the book, Quran(قرأن) and Sunnah(سنّه); imply that whoever seeks to harm Rasool Ullah(ﷺ) or belittle him,
then he should be killed, even if it is very small thing.
In fact; Al Iman Malik(الامام مالك) said; if someone says that the button of Rasool Ullah ﷺ is dirty, then he should be executed,
even if it is as small as saying that, then this person should be executed.
And then Qazi Ayyaz(قاضى عياض) says;
ولا نعلم خلافا فى السباحة دم بين العلماء والأنصاروسلف الامة
And we don't know any different opinion.
This is a consensus, and we don't know any different opinion.
Now, brothers and sisters! any one of you who have studied Asool Ul Fiqh(اصول الفقہ) would realize that Ijma(اجماع) is Hujjah(حجه);
that Ijma(اجماع), when the scholars have a consensus on something, it is just like Quran(قرأن) and sunnah(سنّه);
because Rasool Ullah(ﷺ) says;
لا تجتمع أمتي على ضلالة
My Ummah(امّه) cannot have a consensus on something that is wrong.
Al-Imam Malik(امام مالك) says; Whether Muslim or Kafir(کافر), it doesn't make a difference.
He should be killed without warning.
And then he mentions the story.
He said that
Al-Khalifa Haroon Al-Rashid(الخليفه هارون الرّشيد), he asked Imam Malik (امام مالك) about a man who has spoken against Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
And then Al-Rashid(الرّشيد) told Imam Malik (امام مالك); that the fuqaha(فقهاء) of Iraq(عراق), gave him a fatwa(فتوى) to flogge this man.
So Al-Rashid(الرّشيد) is telling Imam Malik (امام مالك) that there is someone who spoke against Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
And then we asked the some Fuqaha(فقهاء) in Iraq(عراق);
and they gave a fatwa(فتوى) that he should be flogged rather than killing him, he should be flogged.
What did Imam Malik (امام مالك) says?
فغضب امام مالك
Imam Malik (امام مالك) was angry, and he said;
يا أمير المؤمنين ، ما بقاء الأمة بعد شتم نبيها
من شتم الأنبياء قتل، وَمَنْ شَتَمَ أَصْحَابَ النَّبِيِّ - صَلَّى اللَّهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ - جُلِدَ
He said; Oh Ameer Al-Mumineen(اميرالمومنين)! how can the Ummah(امّه) survive when its Prophet is cursed?
Whoever curses the prophets should be executed; and whoever curses the companions of Rasool Ullah(ﷺ), then he should be flogged.
This is the response of Imam Malik (امام مالك) in such a situation, he told the Khalifa;
and he was very angry when he heard this.
He was very angry at this so called Fuqaha(فقهاء) who gave this false and wrong Fatwa(فتوى).
He said; there's a difference between speaking against Rasool Ullah ﷺ, and speaking against Sahaba(صحابه),
if you speak against Rasool Ullah(ﷺ); you are executed, put to death.
If you speak against the Companions, then you are flogged.
And now listen at the comments of Al-Qazi Ayyaz(القاضى عياض).
Al-Qazi Ayyaz(القاضى عياض) said;
كذا وقع في هذه الحكاية، ورواها غير واحد من أصحاب مناقب مالك
He said; this story was narrated to us by more than one person from the companions of Malik(مالك);
and the ones who wrote books about him.
And then he says;
ولاادرى من هؤلآءالفقهاءبالعراق
He said; I have no idea, Al-Qazi Ayyaz(القاضى عياض) was saying;
I have no clue who these scholars from Iraq(عراق) are?
Who would give such a Fatwa(فتوى)?
And we have already mentioned, the opinion of the scholars of Iraq(عراق) that he should be executed.
And then he justifies the situation.
What did he say?
He said;
فلعلهم ممن لم يشهر بعلم
Probably they are from those scholars who are not known to be scholarly.
أو من لا يوثق بفتوای
Or they are those whom we cannot trust their Fatwa(فتوى).
أو يميل به هواه
Or there are those who follow their desires.
أو يكون ما قاله يحمل على غير السب
Or probably what this man said is not really cursing,
and there's a difference of opinion whether it is cursing or not.
It's something that is not clear.
So the Khalifa(خليفه) did not clarify that to Imam Malik (امام مالك).
Or probably this is a man who cursed Rasool Ullah ﷺ, but then he made tobah(توبه), because;
الإجماع على قتل من سبه كما قدمناه
Because it is the consensus of the scholars, that whoever curses Rasool Ullah ﷺ, should be killed.
Now, brothers and sisters! while doing research for this talk, I came across some very, very strange Fatwa(فتوى).
It's amazing; how some people will fall all over themselves, to please the enemies of Allah.
Allahعزَوجلَ says;
فترى الذين في قلوبهم مرض يسارعون فيهم يقولون نخشى أن تصيبنا دائرة
You see some of those who have disease in their hearts.
Hastening towards them, saying; we fear lest the calamity shall befall us.
They are Munafiqeen(منافقين); and they have this disease in their hearts, and they fear that if they speak out,
then a calamity will befall them, because they fear the enemies of Allah more than they fear Allahعزَوجلَ.
The Muslims in the Muslim world, they came out in a spontaneous reaction,
because they were angry by what they heard.
And the Muslims, these Muslims; these simple Muslims,
they have love of Rasool Ullah ﷺ in their heart.
This is their fitrah(فطره).
They're not scholars, but they're Muslims who love Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
They naturally came out to the streets to demonstrate.
Now we might disagree, we might agree with this demonstration thing or disagree,
and we might argue on the benefit of it and what eventually it is beneficial or not.
But the thing is, we know we need to look at the spirit that drove the Muslims to the street.
It is their fitrah(فطره), their love of Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
And they burned flags, and they did this and that.
Now Subhan-Allah(سبحان الله) the Ulama(علماء) rather than coming out
some of these scholars, rather than coming out,
and clarifying to the masses the responsibility and the Hukkam(حكم) of Sharia(شريعه) and this,
as Allahعزَوجلَ says;
لَتُبَيِّنُنَّهُ لِلنَّاسِ وَلاَ تَكْتُمُونَهُ
that the role of the Scholars is to clarify things for the people and not to hide it.
They did not clarify the things, they in fact, confuse the people,
rather than tell them what the Hukkam(حكم) of Allah is, they condemned them for demonstration.
They condemned them for burning flags.
They condemned them for going out in the streets,
and some of them went as far as condemning them for boycotting Danish products,
because it's not conducive for building the relationships between us and them,
and we need to build the bridges and bridge the gaps and all of that nonsense.
Where is the Hukkam(حكم) of Allah عزَوجلَ?
How come it was not clarified, if you cannot speak the truth, then stay quiet.
مَن كان يؤمن بالله واليوم الآخر فليقل خيرًا أو ليصمت
Whoever believes in Allah and the Last day, should either speak the truth and say good or stay quiet?
You have these people who are wearing the cloak of scholarship,
and they are deceiving the people and telling them that they shouldn't do this and they shouldn't do that,
and they're condemning what the people did.
What did they do?
The people went out to demonstrate and they wanted to boycott Danish products.
I mean, these are things that are more befitting of followers of Gandhi than followers of Muhammad(ﷺ).
Who said;
انا نبي الرحمة وانا نبي الملحمة
I am the Prophet of mercy, and I am the Prophet of war.
Muhammad(ﷺ), who said;
بعثت بالسيف بين يدي الساعة
I was sent with the sword before the day of judgment,
حتى يُعبدَ اللهُ وحدَه
Until Allah is worshiped alone.
أُمرتُ أن أُقاتل الناسَ
I was instructed to fight the people,
and he told the people of Quraish(قريش ) to commit them, I came to you with slaughter.
We are followers of Muhammad ﷺ were not followers of Gandhi, we should know who we are,
and we should know who are we dealing ,with we're dealing with Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
This is blasphemy against Rasool Ullah.
And then things got worse.
You have this evil thing of a human being this Swedish guy, Lars vils, who drew Muhammad ﷺ, Astagfirullah(استغفرالله العظيم).
And it's even difficult for him to speak these words.
He drew Muhammad ﷺ, in the form of a dog.
And then you have these scoundrels coming out giving a Fatwa(فتوى) to condemn those who threatened him,
rather than speak out against this kufr(كفر), and rather than show the people what the Hukkam(حكم) of Sharia(شريعه) is,
you only come out to condemn Muslims.
Where is fulfilling the role of Elm(علم) one should either fulfill that role and speak the truth and speak the Haq
or take out that clock of scholarship and stay at home.
We are dealing with Rasool Ullah ﷺ, Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه) told the people, when you see me, grab his head,
tear him apart with your swords.
That is what Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه) did, but we have now Muhammad Bin Muslimah(محمدبن مسلمه) today.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ is to be defended by ourselves and by our wealth and by everything that we own.
This is our duty towards the Messenger of Allah صلوات اللہ وسلام علیہ, and we want to say, just like what Al-Qazi Ayyaz(القاضى عياض) said;
We have no clue who these scholars are, and we would give the same words that Al-Qazi Ayyaz(القاضى عياض) said;
Probably they are not known for having Elm(علم); or we cannot trust their Fatwa(فتوى), or they are people who follow their desires.
Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) said;
وهذاالفعل ھو نوم من الجهادوالاغلاب على الكافرين والمنافقين واظهاردين الله عزّوجلّ والى كلمةومعلوم انّ هذا واجب
فعلم انّ قتل السّاب واجب فى الجمله وحيث جا ذالعفو له فانّما هو فى من كان مقدورا عليه
He said; It is Wajib(واجب); it is mandatory; to kill the one who curses the Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
And he said; If there's any examples otherwise in Seerah(سيره); it is because they have come to him,
and they have announced their Toba(توبه), and they have become Muslim.
But if they don't, then the Hukkam(حكم) remains.
And he said;
فيعلم العاقل أن سب رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم جناية لها موقع يزيد على عامة الجنايات
He said; Cursing Rasool Ullah ﷺ is a crime, that is greater than other crimes.
بحيث يستحق صاحبها من العقوبة مالا يستحقه غيره
And that is why the punishment is more than other crimes.
وإن كان كافراً حربياً مبالغاً في محاربة المسلمين ،
وأن وجوب الانتصار ممن كان هذا حاله كان مؤكداً في الدين
And if such a person is a Kafir(كافر) who is fighting the Muslims, then it is mandatory to give victory for Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
والسعي في إهدار دمه من أفضل الأعمال
And seeking to spill his blood is one of the greatest deeds.
وأوجبها
And one of the most mandatory deeds.
وأحقها بالمسارعة
And it is a deed that one should hasten towards.
وابتغاء رضوان الله تعالى فيه ، وأبلغ الجهاد الذي كتبه الله على عباده وفرضه عليهم
That is one of the greatest forms of Jihad Fee Sabil Lillah(جهادفى سبيل الله).
These are the words of Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه).
These are the words of our scholars.
Now, some of the arguments that are presented is that Rasool Ullah ﷺ, when the Jews came to him, and said Assaam o Alaykum(السام عليكم ),
rather than saying Assalam o Alaykum(السلام عليكم ); they said Assam o Alaykum(السّام عليكم).
Which means may death befall you.
Ayesha(عائشه), she cursed them, and that Rasool Ullah ﷺ told her that Allahعزَوجلَ loves leniency,
ان الله يحب الرفق في كل شيء
And he told her not to curse them.
So they say this is how we should deal with these people.
This argument, Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) and Al-Qazi Ayyaz(القاضى عياض)  did not leave it, without responding to and refuting.
Al-Qazi Ayyaz(القاضى عياض) said;
This hadith(حديث) and others similar to it, were in the beginning of Islam.
But after that, the Hukkam(حكم) of Sharia(شريعه) is that; they should not be forgiven.
So he said; this is the Hukkam(حكم) that is Mansukh(منسوخ) it's abrogated.
Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) says; Number one, this is not a outwardly clear cursing of Rasool Ullah ﷺ,
because it was something that's not apparent for anyone, or is not apparent for everyone.
And then he also says; that Rasool Ullah ﷺ can forgive, but we cannot.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ, this is Haqq(حق) for him.
It is something that belongs to Him; to forgive or not to forgive, because it is a harm done to him.
So he has the right to forgive, but we don't have that right.
It is a Haqq(حق) of Rasool Ullah ﷺ, and therefore he is the one who can forgive.
For example, somebody takes money from me, he steals money from me, and then you forgive him.
It's not of your business.
How could you forgive him?
I'm the one who need to forgive him.
So it is up to Rasool Ullah ﷺ to forgive or not.
Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) says; After Rasool Ullah ﷺ passed away, we cannot forgive anyone.
We can forgive people when they harm us, but not when they harm Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
Another argument; is that the Kuffar(كفّار) they curse Allahعزَوجلَ, and they say that Allah has a son, when they talk about Eesa(عیسی).
So that is something greater.
Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) says;
When they say that about Allah, they don't really mean that they want to curse Allah.
It is their belief, and they honestly believe in that.
And when they say that they don't intend to curse.
But when they speak about Rasool Ullah ﷺ, they're intending to harm the Muslims, and they're intending to speak against Islam.
And therefore the two are different.
A few points to close with.
Number one, the defamation of Muhammad ﷺ will not harm him.
It doesn't harm him.
Rasool Ullah ﷺ is one honored and his name is Muhammad(محمّد), the most praised one, at every single moment of the day around the globe.
In every different time zone, there is a minerate that is calling to Adhan(اذان) and saying;
اشهدانّ محمّدارسول الله
And there are angels that are saying صلى الله علي سیدنا محمد.
And Allahعزَوجلَ is making salah(صلاه), on Muhammad ﷺ.
انّ الله وملائكته يصلّون على النّبى
And there are believers all over the world who are making Salah(صلاه) on Rasool Ullah ﷺ.
So what these villains would say against Rasool Ullah ﷺ would not harm him, but it is a harm of us.
It is the sin on our behalf, to allow the defamation of Muhammad ﷺ to happen.
So we are the ones who are harmed.
We are the ones who should be concerned, not Muhammad ﷺ, this doesn't harm Muhammad ﷺ.
The second thing, even though this thing angers us, it is a sign, that the defeat of the Kuffar(كفّار) is near,
because Ibn Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) says;
Many Muslims trust worthy people of expertise and Fiqh(فقہ) spoke many times about their experiences
when they would surround castles and cities in Hasham(الشّام),
when they would surround the Christians, they said; We would surround the castle or the city for a month or more,
and our Besiege is doing nothing, and our besieging of them is doing nothing.
And we are almost going to give up and leave.
And then when the people of that town or castle, fortress start cursing Rasool Ullah ﷺ, suddenly it falls in our hands.
And sometimes the delay wouldn't be even a day or two, and then it would be opened by force.
He said; So we would take it as a glad tiding
when we would hear them curse Rasool Ullah ﷺ, even though our hearts would be filled with hatred,
but we would see it as a glad tiding because it's a sign of our coming victory.
And that is the meaning of the Ayah(آية) of Surat Al-Kausar(سورة الكوثر);
ان شانئك هو الابتر
Indeed your enemy is the one, who is cut off.
So Allahعزَوجلَ will cut off the enemies of Muhammad ﷺ,
and this affair that is happening now is one of the worst events, or incidents of cursing Muhammad ﷺ.
In fact, it might be the worst in our history,
because it started out with one newspaper in Denmark,
and then many governments and many newspapers around the world showed their solidarity.
Under the pretext of freedom of speech,
they showed their solidarity, and the cartoons went all over the world,
and then you had the incident of this Swedish cartoons,
which depicted Muhammad ﷺ in the worst and it is one of the worst forms of cursing that we have ever heard of.
And then you now have the abuse of the book of Allahعزَوجلَ in ways that we have never heard of,
using it as toilet paper and target and shooting at the book of Allahعزَوجلَ for target practice.
So what is happening now and the enormous extent of it, even though it angers every Muslim,
but it should also be a sign that the end of this Kuffar(كفر) is near.
Last point, brothers and sisters! we as a Ummah(امّه), as Muslims, should never forget,
during the crusade, the sixth crusade against the Muslims,
when they attacked the town of Dmiat in Egypt in year 615,
and after the Crusaders, they occupied Demyat.
The Ayyubi Amir(ایوبی امیر) Muhammad Al-Kamil(محمّد الكامل).
He was in Mansoorah(منصورۃ) fighting them.
It is said that there was one of these men from the Crusaders,
who used to come out every day and curse Muhammad saw him with the worst words, and he would do that on a daily basis.
And the Ameer(امیر) of the Muslims Muhammad Al-Kamil(محمّد الكامل) would just wish if he could get his hands on this man and capture him.
And he engraved his face in his memory.
And this is year 615, three years later, the crusade failed, and they left.
But this particular man, he went on to carry on the fight to Hasham(الشّام).
And Subhan-Allah(سبحان الله); He fell into custody of the Muslims,
and Al Amir Muhammad Al-Kamil(محمّد الكامل) remembered him.
And we're talking about year 625, ten years later.
So he takes him away, and he sends him to Madinah(مدينه) and gives command to the Emir of Madinah(مدينه)
to slaughter him in front of the grave of Muhammad ﷺ on the day of Jumah(جمعه).
Ten years later and he did not forget.
So, brothers and sisters! We ask Allahعزَوجل, that he raises among us, men and women,
that, as Allah says;
لا يخافون في الله لومة لائم
They do not fear in the sake of Allah the blame of the blamers,
who would make the Kuffar(كفّار) realize that they, by committing blasphemy against our beloved Muhammad(محمّد),
have actually walked straight into a hornet's nest, and that the dust of this will never settle down.
اقولو قولی ھذا واستغفرللہ العظیم ولی ولکم
فستغفرہ انہ ھوالغفور الرحیم
وصلی اللہ علی سیدنا محمد وعلی آلہ وصحبہ وسلم
والسلام و علیکم ورحمۃ اللہ وبرکاتہ